Daniel Cárdenas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Monterrey, NL. México

🛘 (+52) 8114140740 | 🔀 danielcardeenas@gmail.com | 🏕 danielcardeenas.github.io | 🖸 danielcardeenas | 🖹 danielcardeenas

Summary.

Full-stack developer with 10+ years of experience in building web apps and systems. I've developed expertise on Enterprise Frontend engineering B2B and B2C products high performance and high compatibility.

Mostly code in Javascript/Typescript and Python using tools like React, Angular, NextJS, NodeJS.

To deploy my applications I mainly use: Vercel, GCP Cloud Run, Cloudflare

What to expect from me / My strengths:

- 1. Skilled at building projects from scratch, delivering MVPs quickly
- 2. Create visually stunning and intuitive UIs
- 3. Deliver clean, well-tested code
- 4. Quickly contribute to existing projects without onboarding assistance

In my free time:

I actively contribute to open source in Github. Also navigate trough Dribble / Behance and implement designs I like using various tech stacks.

Stack.

Frontend: Angular, React, Javascript, PWAs, React Native, Expo, SASS, CSS, HTML

Backend: NextJS, Remix, NodeJS, .NET Core, Bun

DevOps: Google Cloud Platform, Firebase, Cloudflare, Vercel, Docker, Supabase

Database:PostgresSQL, GraphQL, NoSQL, Neon (Pg)Programming:Typescript, Python, C#, Rust, C++, Java, GoMicroservices:SocketIO, Kafka, Aeron, Vertx, IterableTesting:Playwright, Puppeteer, Browserless, Jest

Work Experience and Freelancing

Luxoft Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 2022 - Current

- Lead development of robust main application built with NextJS/React and PostgreSQL / GraphQL.
- Automated shipment across the world with **Aftership**
- Automatic paper PDF on demand generation for client requests with Google Cloud Function and Puppeteer
- Playwright E2E Testing suite across entire application from single component functionality (**Jest**) to entire user submission process including emails (**Mailtrap**)
- Configurable dynamic complex form generation from single **API** endpoint that renders to the user and keeps the same beautiful look and feel. Based on the configuration files, E2E tests are created automatically.

DHL Remote

SENIOT FRONTEND ENGINEER (FREELANCE / CONTRATIST)

2022 - Current

· Web application system development for DHL tracking of custom deliveries for B2B. Mostly Angular

Genie Terex Remote

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 2022 - 2022

Here I took a very hard algorithmic test in C++ to qualify. I wanted to try working with Low-level microchip programming since I was always
interested but I didn't enjoy it as much as doing Web Development. So I leaved after 6 months of working

Cemex (Neoris). Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

2016 - 2022

Leaded and created from scratch the frontend main application Angular for Cemex Go. Currenlty supports more 20+ countries consuming
different business rules for each from Azure Microservices

Stukent Remote

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCE / CONTRATIST)

2021 - 2022

- Created a lot of modular Courseware components using **Storybook .NET Core** and **Angular**. Ensuring seamless integration.
- Managed Azure functions in C# for data handling in simulations, ensuring seamless operations.

OXXO Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE & LEAD DEVELOPER

2014 - 2016

Created from scratch kiosk system for OXXO stores, enhancing POS connectivity and uptime. Using iOS native development Swift and
Objective-C. Programmed entire UI from given designs from the UI team

- Led the design and deployment of a 24/7 self-updating kiosk system, enhancing POS integration and operational efficiency across select Oxxo stores.
- Designed the DB (MySQL) for flexibility using resources already provided by the OXXO Stores.
- · Transmitted the order via FTP with to the physical POS. Printed the order ticket for the end user via Bluetooth using printer SDK

Epicor Software Corp

Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

2012 - 2014

- Supported and customized CRM 'Clientele' in .NET, enhancing functionality and user experience.
- Contributed to the development of web ERP 'P21' using ASP MVC, improving system efficiency.
- Developed software in **C#** and **SQL**, ensuring robust and scalable solutions.

Projects.

PROJECTS

2024	🗘 Surebet, Realtime sportsbook arbitrage opportunity finder and automatic placer. Built with NodeJS	Ноте
2019	🗘 Sulla, Sulla is a NodeJS library which provides a high-level API control to Whatsapp	Home
2017	• QuandlCpp, Efficient Quandl C++ library on top of .NET	Home
2017	🗘 leind-stocks , Implementation of the steps of the William O'Neil book trough all possible stocks.	Home
2016	🗘 Whatsapp framework, Whatsapp api framework built in Python	Home
2014	🗘 Audio Stego, Audio Stenography library	Home

FREELANCER

2016 Quandl retriver (tecenergy.ca), Quandl big data retriever for data science firm active in financial electricity markets. Built in C# and PostgreSQL.

% **Profet CRM (Full-stack)**, One of my firsts professional jobs. Created a custom CRM system for a marketing local company built on .NET and used **jQuery** (Angular didn't existed at this time)

% Ion Water distributor ERP (Full-stack), My first proffesional job. Developed a whole custom ERP system
from scratch for a local water company. Architecture of the application is based on modules which are easily
added to the system as the client needs. This system is deployed into the client local servers (and still
running). The stack used here is SQL and .NET MVC.

Remote

Education

UANL - Facultad de Ciencias Físico Matemáticas

Monterrey, MX

Physics

2023

· Study of the fundamental principles of physics, including mechanics, electromagnetism, thermodynamics, and quantum mechanics.

UANL - Facultad de Ingeniería Mecánica Eléctrica

Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2011 - Exp. Nov. 2015

 Study of software development principles, algorithms, data structures, and programming languages. Specialized in web development and cloud computing.